<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <author>LibreOps</author>
  <title>LibreOps - dns</title>
  <link href="https://libreops.cc/feed.xml" rel="self" />
  <link href="https://libreops.cc/" />
  <icon>https://libreops.cc/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://libreops.cc/static/img/</logo>
  <updated>2020-04-16T12:14:21Z</updated>
  
    <entry>
      <title>doh-cli, a simple DoH client</title>
      <link href="https://libreops.cc/2019/12/25/doh-cli/"/>
      <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[
          <p>A couple months ago, we announced a public and free DNS service, so people can have encrypted DNS in their browsers and systems. We support both DNS over HTTPS (DoH) and DNS over TLS and our DoH service has two endpoints, the default <code>/dns-query</code> and one for blocking trackers and ads <code>/ads</code>. You can visit <a href="https://libredns.gr/">our page</a> for more info.</p>
<h2>dns</h2>
<p>What is <strong>DNS</strong>?</p>
<p>Domain Name Service in a nutshell is when you are asking directions to find where Wikipedia is in the internet. Your browser does not know, so it will ask your computer. Your computer will ask your internet provider and your internet provider will ask someone else till they find the correct answer. In the end, your browser will know where to go and this is how you are visiting Wikipedia.</p>
<p>You need to trust all the above parties, to give you the correct answer and everybody knows that you are visiting Wikipedia.</p>
<h2>doh</h2>
<p>What is <strong>DoH</strong> (DNS Queries over HTTPS)?</p>
<p>It's the implementation of <a href="https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc8484">RFC 8484</a>. This is a way for your browser to ask where to find Wikipedia, without exposing to everybody that you want to visit Wikipedia! Still you need someone to ask for directions, but now both your question and the answer are encrypted. So you have privacy.</p>
<h2>let's get technical</h2>
<p>What is <strong>RFC 8484</strong>?</p>
<p>In the above rfc, your client (eg. browser) asks your DNS via HTTP/2 representational state transfer (<strong>REST</strong>). DoH clients and servers need to sent a <code>application/dns-message</code> content (question/answer) and encode both the question and the answer in a <code>bace64url</code> message. Usually is GET, but POST is also supported on some servers.</p>
<h2>doh-cli</h2>
<p>So, today, we introduce <strong><a href="https://gitlab.com/libreops/doh-cli">doh-cli</a></strong>, a simple command line DoH client, written in python. You can use <strong>doh-cli</strong> as a binary client in your system. We support a few DoH public servers to test, and of course both LibreDNS DoH endpoints</p>
<p><a href="https://gitlab.com/libreops/doh-cli">Source Code</a>
<a href="https://pypi.org/project/doh-cli/">PyPi</a></p>
<h2>install it</h2>
<p>It is super easy</p>
<p><code>pip3 install doh-cli</code></p>
<p>or if python3 is your default python</p>
<p><code>pip install doh-cli</code></p>
<h2>howto use it?</h2>
<p>Just ask your favorite DoH server (default is <code>https://doh.libredns.gr/dns-query</code>)</p>
<p>eg.</p>
<p><code>doh-cli libredns.gr A</code></p>
<p>and use help to see all the options</p>
<p><code>doh-cli --help</code></p>
<h2>Why default output is json?</h2>
<p>With modern tools and with multiline output, it is best to support a serialized format so you can use doh-cli with your tools. But if you dont like it:</p>
<p><code>doh-cli --output plain libredns.gr A</code></p>
<p>You can see all the options and help, on the project's page.</p>
<p><img alt="doh-cli" src="/2019/12/25/doh-cli/doh-cli.png" /></p>
        ]]>
      </content>
      <published>2019-12-25 19:00:00</published>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Mobile Privacy with DoH using Firefox and LibreDNS</title>
      <link href="https://libreops.cc/2019/12/21/libredns-mobile-firefox/"/>
      <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[
          <h2>DNS over HTTPS on Mobile</h2>
<p>Using DoH on mobile phones is not an easy task.
There are not many applications nor settings on the major operating systems for mobile devices that support DoH to resolve domain names.
Firefox provides an easy solution in order to use DoH on your phone with your browser.
In this article, we provide steps to do that with the help of Firefox and LibreDNS.</p>
<h2>Firefox on Mobile</h2>
<ul>
<li>Download Firefox for Mobile Devices.</li>
<li>Open Firefox and write in the address bar <code>about:config</code>.</li>
<li>Write in the search bar <code>network.trr.uri</code> and change the value of the preference to the URL of <strong>LibreDNS</strong> DoH endpoint: <a href="https://doh.libredns.gr/dns-query">https://doh.libredns.gr/dns-query</a>.</li>
</ul>
<p><img alt="mobile1" src="/2019/12/21/libredns-mobile-firefox/mobile1.png" /></p>
<ul>
<li>Write in the search bar <code>network.trr.mode</code> and use <strong>2</strong> as value if you want to use LibreDNS as the default DoH provider and use your prexisting DNS provider as a fallback.
    Use <strong>3</strong> as a value if you want to use <strong>only</strong> LibreDNS without any fallback, for more options visit: <a href="https://wiki.mozilla.org/Trusted_Recursive_Resolver">https://wiki.mozilla.org/Trusted_Recursive_Resolver</a>.</li>
</ul>
<p><img alt="mobile2" src="/2019/12/21/libredns-mobile-firefox/mobile2.png" /></p>
<ul>
<li>If you choose <strong>3</strong> in <code>network.trr.mode</code> you also need to add the following preference in <code>about:config</code>:
    Search for <code>network.trr.bootstrapAddress</code> in the address bar and change the value to <code>116.202.176.26</code> which is the IP address of LibreDNS.</li>
</ul>
<p><img alt="mobile3" src="/2019/12/21/libredns-mobile-firefox/mobile3.png" /></p>
<ul>
<li>Test the connection with <a href="https://dnsleaktest.com/">https://dnsleaktest.com/</a>, you should only get the following results:</li>
</ul>
<p><img alt="mobile4" src="/2019/12/21/libredns-mobile-firefox/mobile4.png" /></p>
        ]]>
      </content>
      <published>2019-12-21 17:00:00</published>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>LibreDNS, our new encrypted DNS service</title>
      <link href="https://libreops.cc/2019/10/14/libredns/"/>
      <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://libredns.gr" target="_blank"><img alt="LibreDNS" src="/2019/10/14/libredns/libredns.svg" class="w-50"></a></p>
<p>DNS is a very old and essential internet protocol, that we all use daily. But it was built without privacy and secrecy in mind. It lacks encryption, and though it's decentralized in theory, for most people it has a central point of failure (or censorship), their ISP's DNS provider.</p>
<p>In many places ISPs are vulnerable to state censorship and control, obliged to block certain domains or even do metadata retention. People have started using alternative services to get around that, but most well-known DNS providers are commercial entities with a business plan that is in contradiction with privacy.</p>
<p>DNS encrypted protocols have been on the rise lately, with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DNS_over_HTTPS">DoH</a> (DNS over HTTPS) being the one with the biggest support, but also easy of use.</p>
<p><strong>Today we announce our own DNS service</strong>, a public encrypted DNS service, that people can use to maintain secrecy of their dns traffic and bypass censorship.</p>
<p>Its name is <a href="https://libredns.gr/">LibreDNS</a>.</p>
<hr>

<p><em>If you value our work, please consider <a href="https://liberapay.com/libreops/donate">supporting us</a>. We only rely to our contributors.</em></p>
        ]]>
      </content>
      <published>2019-10-14 11:11:11</published>
    </entry>
  
</feed>