<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <author>LibreOps</author>
  <title>LibreOps - dns</title>
  <link href="https://libreops.cc/feed.xml" rel="self" />
  <link href="https://libreops.cc/" />
  <icon>https://libreops.cc/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://libreops.cc/static/img/</logo>
  <updated>2019-12-21T16:37:08Z</updated>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Mobile Privacy with DoH using Firefox and LibreDNS</title>
      <link href="https://libreops.cc/2019/12/21/libredns-mobile-firefox/"/>
      <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[
          <h2>DNS over HTTPS on Mobile</h2>
<p>Using DoH on mobile phones is not an easy task.
There are not many applications nor settings on the major operating systems for mobile devices that support DoH to resolve domain names.
Firefox provides an easy solution in order to use DoH on your phone with your browser.
In this article, we provide steps to do that with the help of Firefox and LibreDNS.</p>
<h2>Firefox on Mobile</h2>
<ul>
<li>Download Firefox for Mobile Devices.</li>
<li>Open Firefox and write in the address bar <code>about:config</code>.</li>
<li>Write in the search bar <code>network.trr.uri</code> and change the value of the preference to the URL of <strong>LibreDNS</strong> DoH endpoint: <a href="https://doh.libredns.gr/dns-query">https://doh.libredns.gr/dns-query</a>.</li>
</ul>
<p><img alt="mobile1" src="/2019/12/21/libredns-mobile-firefox/mobile1.png" /></p>
<ul>
<li>Write in the search bar <code>network.trr.mode</code> and use <strong>2</strong> as value if you want to use LibreDNS as the default DoH provider and use your prexisting DNS provider as a fallback.
    Use <strong>3</strong> as a value if you want to use <strong>only</strong> LibreDNS without any fallback, for more options visit: <a href="https://wiki.mozilla.org/Trusted_Recursive_Resolver">https://wiki.mozilla.org/Trusted_Recursive_Resolver</a>.</li>
</ul>
<p><img alt="mobile2" src="/2019/12/21/libredns-mobile-firefox/mobile2.png" /></p>
<ul>
<li>If you choose <strong>3</strong> in <code>network.trr.mode</code> you also need to add the following preference in <code>about:config</code>: 
    Search for <code>network.trr.bootstrapAddress</code> in the address bar and change the value to <code>116.203.115.192</code> which is the IP address of LibreDNS. </li>
</ul>
<p><img alt="mobile3" src="/2019/12/21/libredns-mobile-firefox/mobile3.png" /></p>
<ul>
<li>Test the connection with <a href="http://dnsleaktest.com/">http://dnsleaktest.com/</a>, you should only get the following results:</li>
</ul>
<p><img alt="mobile4" src="/2019/12/21/libredns-mobile-firefox/mobile4.png" /></p>
        ]]>
      </content>
      <published>2019-12-21 17:00:00</published>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>LibreDNS, our new encrypted DNS service</title>
      <link href="https://libreops.cc/2019/10/14/libredns/"/>
      <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://libredns.gr" target="_blank"><img alt="LibreDNS" src="/2019/10/14/libredns/libredns.svg" class="w-50"></a></p>
<p>DNS is a very old and essential internet protocol, that we all use daily. But it was built without privacy and secrecy in mind. It lacks encryption, and though it's decentralized in theory, for most people it has a central point of failure (or censorship), their ISP's DNS provider.</p>
<p>In many places ISPs are vulnerable to state censorship and control, obliged to block certain domains or even do metadata retention. People have started using alternative services to get around that, but most well-known DNS providers are commercial entities with a business plan that is in contradiction with privacy.</p>
<p>DNS encrypted protocols have been on the rise lately, with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DNS_over_HTTPS">DoH</a> (DNS over HTTPS) being the one with the biggest support, but also easy of use.</p>
<p><strong>Today we announce our own DNS service</strong>, a public encrypted DNS service, that people can use to maintain secrecy of their dns traffic and bypass censorship.</p>
<p>Its name is <a href="https://libredns.gr/">LibreDNS</a>.</p>
<hr>

<p><em>If you value our work, please consider <a href="https://liberapay.com/libreops/donate">supporting us</a>. We only rely to our contributors.</em></p>
        ]]>
      </content>
      <published>2019-10-14 11:11:11</published>
    </entry>
  
</feed>