<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <author>LibreOps</author>
  <title>LibreOps - guide</title>
  <link href="https://libreops.cc/feed.xml" rel="self" />
  <link href="https://libreops.cc/" />
  <icon>https://libreops.cc/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://libreops.cc/static/img/</logo>
  <updated>2021-03-22T16:11:57Z</updated>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Using LibreDNS on iOS 14.x</title>
      <link href="https://libreops.cc/2020/10/14/libredns-ios/"/>
      <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[
          <p>We started our DoH/DoT service, <a href="https://libredns.gr">LibreDNS</a>, to secure (encrypt) our DNS queries and we made this service available to everybody, a year ago to this day!</p>
<p>We are really happy about the adaptation of LibreDNS and in some cases about providing a way to overcome censorship. Althouth we are not a big company/organization but a small team, we try to maintain these projects, keep them up to date and provide stable public services to everyone.</p>
<p>We depend on <a href="https://opencollective.com/libreops/">financial contributions</a> from people who trust and support us into running all of our services. We are always available and open for communication at our <a href="https://riot.im/app/#/room/#libreops:matrix.org">Matrix channel</a>.</p>
<p>So, many thanks to all of you for supporting <strong>LibreDNS</strong>.</p>
<h2>Apple - iOS 14.x</h2>
<p>In apple devices, there was not an easy way to encrypt DNS queries and be protected against DNS leaks. The acceptated method was using cloudflare's 1.1.1.1 that creates a VPN to your mobile device and send your DNS queries throuth their infrastructure.</p>
<p>Recently we came upon this opensource project: <a href="https://github.com/kkk669/DNSecure">DNSecure</a> and we tried it, to see if it can be an alternative method to use <strong>LibreDNS</strong> service on iOS devices.</p>
<h2>Apple Store</h2>
<p>You can download the application from the apple store:
<a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/dnsecure/id1533413232">dnsecure</a></p>
<p><em><strong>Notice:</strong> Requires iOS 14.0 or later.</em></p>
<h3>DoH Settings</h3>
<p>These are the settings to enable LibreDNS - DoH (DNS over https) service:</p>
<p>Servers: <strong>116.202.176.26</strong> <br>
Server URL: <code>https://doh.libredns.gr/dns-query</code></p>
<p><img alt="libredns-doh" src="/2020/10/14/libredns-ios/libredns-doh-dnsecure.png" /></p>
<p>or you can use our no-trackers endpoint:</p>
<p><code>https://doh.libredns.gr/ads</code></p>
<h3>DoT Settings</h3>
<p>To add the DoT (DNS over TLS) support:</p>
<p>Servers: <strong>116.202.176.26</strong> <br>
Server Name: <code>dot.libredns.gr</code></p>
<p><img alt="libredns-dot" src="/2020/10/14/libredns-ios/libredns-dot-dnsecure.png" /></p>
<h2>DNS - VPN</h2>
<p>It is time to enable this DNS service, so go to:</p>
<p><code>General --&gt; VPN &amp; Network --&gt; DNS</code></p>
<p>and enable DNSecure</p>
<p><img alt="libredns-dns-vpn" src="/2020/10/14/libredns-ios/libredns-vpn-ios.jpg" /></p>
<h3>DNS Leak Results</h3>
<p>To verify that your LibreDNS is running, visit
<a href="https://www.dnsleaktest.com/">dnsleattest</a> and run the test; you should see LibreDNS as your DNS server</p>
<p><img alt="dnsleak" src="/2020/10/14/libredns-ios/mobile4.png" /></p>
<hr />
<p><em>If you value our work, please consider <a href="https://opencollective.com/libreops/">supporting us</a>. We only rely to our contributors.</em></p>
        ]]>
      </content>
      <published>2020-10-14 11:00:00</published>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Mobile Privacy with DoH using Firefox and LibreDNS</title>
      <link href="https://libreops.cc/2019/12/21/libredns-mobile-firefox/"/>
      <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[
          <h2>DNS over HTTPS on Mobile</h2>
<p>Using DoH on mobile phones is not an easy task.
There are not many applications nor settings on the major operating systems for mobile devices that support DoH to resolve domain names.
Firefox provides an easy solution in order to use DoH on your phone with your browser.
In this article, we provide steps to do that with the help of Firefox and LibreDNS.</p>
<h2>Firefox on Mobile</h2>
<ul>
<li>Download Firefox for Mobile Devices.</li>
<li>Open Firefox and write in the address bar <code>about:config</code>.</li>
<li>Write in the search bar <code>network.trr.uri</code> and change the value of the preference to the URL of <strong>LibreDNS</strong> DoH endpoint: <a href="https://doh.libredns.gr/dns-query">https://doh.libredns.gr/dns-query</a>.</li>
</ul>
<p><img alt="mobile1" src="/2019/12/21/libredns-mobile-firefox/mobile1.png" /></p>
<ul>
<li>Write in the search bar <code>network.trr.mode</code> and use <strong>2</strong> as value if you want to use LibreDNS as the default DoH provider and use your prexisting DNS provider as a fallback.
    Use <strong>3</strong> as a value if you want to use <strong>only</strong> LibreDNS without any fallback, for more options visit: <a href="https://wiki.mozilla.org/Trusted_Recursive_Resolver">https://wiki.mozilla.org/Trusted_Recursive_Resolver</a>.</li>
</ul>
<p><img alt="mobile2" src="/2019/12/21/libredns-mobile-firefox/mobile2.png" /></p>
<ul>
<li>If you choose <strong>3</strong> in <code>network.trr.mode</code> you also need to add the following preference in <code>about:config</code>:
    Search for <code>network.trr.bootstrapAddress</code> in the address bar and change the value to <code>116.202.176.26</code> which is the IP address of LibreDNS.</li>
</ul>
<p><img alt="mobile3" src="/2019/12/21/libredns-mobile-firefox/mobile3.png" /></p>
<ul>
<li>Test the connection with <a href="https://dnsleaktest.com/">https://dnsleaktest.com/</a>, you should only get the following results:</li>
</ul>
<p><img alt="mobile4" src="/2019/12/21/libredns-mobile-firefox/mobile4.png" /></p>
        ]]>
      </content>
      <published>2019-12-21 17:00:00</published>
    </entry>
  
</feed>