<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <author>LibreOps</author>
  <title>LibreOps - service</title>
  <link href="https://libreops.cc/feed.xml" rel="self" />
  <link href="https://libreops.cc/" />
  <icon>https://libreops.cc/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://libreops.cc/static/img/</logo>
  <updated>2021-03-22T16:16:23Z</updated>
  
    <entry>
      <title>New service, a Mastodon/Twitter cross-poster</title>
      <link href="https://libreops.cc/2021/03/22/konekti/"/>
      <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[
          <p>It's been more than two years since we launched our <a href="https://libretooth.gr/">Mastodon instance</a> and we recently witnessed a spike of new registrations, mainly driven by increased censorship on mainstream social media platforms.</p>
<p>We understand though that many people still want to use Mastodon as a complementary channel along with everything else they use. To better accommodate that we launched a new service that allows you to cross-post between Twitter and Mastodon. It works in both ways and it's very configurable to allow you determine the kind of information you want to publish in either platforms. You only need to connect it with both of them and get through the settings.</p>
<p><strong>You can connect to the service at: <a href="https://konekti.libretooth.gr/">konekti.libretooth.gr</a></strong></p>
<p><img alt="konekti configuration" src="/2021/03/22/konekti/konekti.jpg" /></p>
<p>This service is based on the Open Source project <a href="https://github.com/FedStoa/moa">Moa</a></p>
<hr>

<p><em>If you value our work, please consider <a href="https://opencollective.com/libreops/">supporting us</a>. We only rely to our contributors.</em></p>
        ]]>
      </content>
      <published>2021-03-22 19:00:00</published>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Phasing out our Diaspora pod</title>
      <link href="https://libreops.cc/2020/08/04/diaspora-eol/"/>
      <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[
          <p>Our diaspora pod, <a href="https://librenet.gr">librenet</a>, is the first service we ever set up and got online when the team that today is named LibreOps was initially formed.</p>
<p>The last couple of years our pod has significantly less activity and very few active users. Diaspora as a network has also less activity than it used to, partially because of its development team decision not to adopt the protocol which has been established as the open standard for federated services (ActivityPub). Although federated itself, it remains disconnected from the rest of the networks (what we call Fediverse). At the same time diaspora, as a software, was very difficult to administer and as our pod grew in size it became significantly slower. Effectively not allowing us to provide the level of service we want to the users.</p>
<p>For all these reasons, we believe that librenet.gr has run its course and <strong>we decided to terminate it at October 30th</strong>. We have huge appreciation for all the people that trusted us and this service for all these years. At the same time we still believe there is value in federated services as a big step towards a decentralized internet. That's why we maintain our own <a href="https://libretooth.gr/">mastodon instance</a>.</p>
<p>We are a small team, working voluntarily, in a non-hierarchical way and depend on <a href="https://opencollective.com/libreops/">financial contributions</a> from people who trust and support us into running all of our services. We are always available and open for communication at our <a href="https://riot.im/app/#/room/#libreops:matrix.org">Matrix channel</a>.</p>
<p><img alt="diaspora" src="/2020/08/04/diaspora-eol/diaspora2.png" /></p>
<hr>

<p><em>If you value our work, please consider <a href="https://opencollective.com/libreops/">supporting us</a>. We only rely to our contributors.</em></p>
        ]]>
      </content>
      <published>2020-08-04 11:45:00</published>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Two New LibreOps Services</title>
      <link href="https://libreops.cc/2020/04/21/two-new-librops-services/"/>
      <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[
          <p>We are happy and proud to launch our two new LibreOps services.</p>
<p>Our (Jitsi) Meet instance, the popular open source application that provides high quality, scalable video conferences. 
We hope that can people can communicate without logs but with privacy and security, especially these difficult COVID-19 times.
<a href="https://meet.libreops.cc" target="_blank"><img alt="Jitsi Meet" src="/2020/04/21/two-new-librops-services/meet.svg" class="w-25"></a></p>
<p>Our public DNS Resolver instance, named RadicalDNS. 
The motivation for this service was that the DoH/DoT encrypted DNS Service (LibreDNS), we're already operating, is unfortuanately not yet able to support legacy devices like phones, TVs or even home routers. Thus we wanted to provide and easy and useful public DNS alternative. The goal is to offer a public DNS service that people can use to maintain the secrecy of their DNS traffic, but also circumvent censorship. We don't keep logs, but we also filter ads and trackers. 
<a href="https://libreops.cc/radicaldns.html" target="_blank"><img alt="radicalDNS" src="/2020/04/21/two-new-librops-services/radicaldns.svg" class="w-25"></a></p>
<hr>

<p><em>If you value our work, please consider <a href="https://opencollective.com/libreops/">supporting us</a>. We only rely to our contributors.</em></p>
        ]]>
      </content>
      <published>2020-04-21 13:00:00</published>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>LibreDNS, our new encrypted DNS service</title>
      <link href="https://libreops.cc/2019/10/14/libredns/"/>
      <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://libredns.gr" target="_blank"><img alt="LibreDNS" src="/2019/10/14/libredns/libredns.svg" class="w-50"></a></p>
<p>DNS is a very old and essential internet protocol, that we all use daily. But it was built without privacy and secrecy in mind. It lacks encryption, and though it's decentralized in theory, for most people it has a central point of failure (or censorship), their ISP's DNS provider.</p>
<p>In many places ISPs are vulnerable to state censorship and control, obliged to block certain domains or even do metadata retention. People have started using alternative services to get around that, but most well-known DNS providers are commercial entities with a business plan that is in contradiction with privacy.</p>
<p>DNS encrypted protocols have been on the rise lately, with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DNS_over_HTTPS">DoH</a> (DNS over HTTPS) being the one with the biggest support, but also easy of use.</p>
<p><strong>Today we announce our own DNS service</strong>, a public encrypted DNS service, that people can use to maintain secrecy of their dns traffic and bypass censorship.</p>
<p>Its name is <a href="https://libredns.gr/">LibreDNS</a>.</p>
<hr>

<p><em>If you value our work, please consider <a href="https://liberapay.com/libreops/donate">supporting us</a>. We only rely to our contributors.</em></p>
        ]]>
      </content>
      <published>2019-10-14 11:11:11</published>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Running a Tor Relay</title>
      <link href="https://libreops.cc/2019/03/01/libreonion/"/>
      <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[
          <p>For those new on <a href="https://www.torproject.org/">Tor</a>, it's a group of volunteer-operated servers that allows people to improve their privacy and security on the Internet, but also circumventing censorship. For a more detailed overview check the video at the end of the post.</p>
<p><img alt="libreonion" src="/2019/03/01/libreonion/libreonion.png" class="float-left"></p>
<p>In early February we started experimenting with running a Tor Relay. We chose to do that in a Greek IP address, to contribute to Tor's network diversity. At the momemnt there were only 40 Tor Relays running from Greece.</p>
<p>Almost a month later our relay has already generate 3.2TB of traffic. You can see some graphs below, and on <a href="https://metrics.torproject.org/rs.html#details/E8D114B3C78D8E6E7FEB1004650DD632C2143C9E">Tor Metrics</a> website.</p>
<p>We are really happy to contribute on Tor, and hopefully we will run more relays in the future. <strong>If you want to help us run more relays, you can <a href="https://liberapay.com/libreops/donate">donate</a>.</strong></p>
<p><img alt="vnstat" src="/2019/03/01/libreonion/vnstat.png" /></p>
<div class="embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9">
  <video controls="" preload="none" poster="https://www.torproject.org/images/tor-animation.jpg" class="embed-responsive-item">
    <source src="https://www.torproject.org/videos/Tor_Animation_en.mp4" type="video/mp4">
    <track label="English" kind="captions" src="https://www.torproject.org/videos/en.vtt" srclang="en" default="">
  </video>
</div>
        ]]>
      </content>
      <published>2019-03-01 14:02:21</published>
    </entry>
  
</feed>